Sufyan Saleem

Date of Birth: 4 Jan 1996 Marital Status: Single

Address: Asgårdvegen 23, D3, 9016 Tromsø

Website: https://sufyansaleem.net/ Email: sufyansalim94@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

I am a 29 years old Software Developer who loves to play with different technologies. And I am looking forward to a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with a friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Aido AS

July 2021 - present

Full Stack Developer

Working for this service provider agency, which provides smart solutions for managing rotations and shift planning. My main roles include developing Hybrid Mobile Application, Web Application.

Aido As

- Working on their main product first react native app then expo app worked with sentry, bitrise, bitbucket.
- App available on <u>iOs</u> and <u>Android</u>
- React Native, Expo, Bitbucket, Sentry Bitrise, Apple Appstore, Google Play Store.

Linknbit

Dec 2020

MERN Stack Developer

Worked as part time project based remote job as MERN Stack developer.

Missoq

- Ecommerce Store.
- Worked on both frontend and backend.React, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB, Digital Ocean.

Decklaration

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

MERN Stack Engineer

Working for NY based design Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications, Backend and Hybrid Mobile Applications.

Mertium

- Similar to Bloomberg.
- I developed the frontend based on a template. HTML, CSS, Less, React

Hybrid, Norway

Remote, Pakistan

Remote, Pakistan

Medtigo

- Provides services for hospitals
- I developed the Backend in
- Nodejs, Express, MSQL, Sequelize, Node mailer, Security for XSS and SQL Injection. Deployment on Amazon

Linknbit

Jan 2019 – May 2020

Software Engineer

Working for Software Development and IT Solutions Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications and Hybrid Mobile Applications.

Kyla App

- It is a Mobile App that know your laws recommend actions and contact a lawyer with location and details.
- Developed the backend in NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Node mailer, Geolocation, Security for XSS and NOSQL Injection. Deployed on Amazon.

Dynasty Unleashed Models

- Modeling agency App for Fashion designers and marketers and hiring models.
- Developed part of Front-End
- in React/React-Native & part of Deployment to Firebase & Google Play Store.

Dokkani.co

- Ecommerce Mobile App.
- Users can register, select products, add products to cart. The users add products to their wish list and checkout. The project was abandoned on the last stage due to funds not provided and worked on both frontend and backend.
- React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Word Press API, Woo Commerce API.Native Base

Yogurt App

- Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate.
- I developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo,Native Base

SmartsAid

NGO App for refuges

Islamabad, Pakistan

 Worked on both the frontend and backend.React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Firebase, Rest API,React Native Elements

Side Projects

2022 - FYP

Nudging based on users preference - Fitbit

- Developed an app in my Final year project at University of Tromso, where user vital data is taken from a FitBit device and nudged with notifications to not be inactive and recommended activities based on user's preferences.
- Developed in Expo, Firebase, Python, Flask, Rest API, React Native Paper.

2022

Migraine Prediction With Empatica E4

- Worked on frontend and device integration as a project in university.
- Designed and implemented the mobile application frontend using React Native and Expo. And integrated the Empatica E4 wristband via Bluetooth to collect physiological signals (BVP, HR, temperature, accelerometer, EDA) for migraine research.
- Collaborated with team members who managed backend services; focused on user interface, device connectivity, and secure data transfer to APIs.
- Ensured user-friendly experience with interactive symptom logging and validation mechanisms.

2018 - FYP

Currency Recognition & Conversion

- Developed an app in my Final Year project at IMSciences Peshawar where users can scan currency notes and it will tell which currency it is and how much it is and show the exchange rate in USD.
- Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB

2021

Chord Paper

- Worked on it as a project at the university.Implementation of the chord paper, a scalable peer to peer lookup for internet applications.
- A key value store.
- Made in NodeJs, Python, Shell, Bash and tested at the UIT Cluster.

RuneScape RPG

- Worked on it when I was in mid-school.Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game for me to level up when I was at school.
- Developed in Java

Note: For more projects checkout the website mentioned in the header of the resume.

References: The contact person references can be provided upon request.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science, grade C UiT, Tromsø (Aug 2020 – Dec 2022)

Internet of things and Al Specialist Course PIAIC, Islamabad (2019), Only First Quadrant

BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78 Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

F.Sc – Pre-Engineering, grade B ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

10 Matric, grade ARacines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE

Specialities

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

Social Links





Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo Vanilla Javascript, Node JS, Express. Mongoose, Sequelize, Firebase, Mongo DB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, Git, Heroku, Netlify, Digital Ocean, Amazon cloud, Rest Api, GraphQL, MVC, Bash, Rust, Word press, Xcode, Android Studio, Chatgpt, Copilot Linux, WinOs, MacOs

LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES

Languages

English Urdu Pashto, Basic Norsk

Hobbies

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking,Gym, Indoor Rock Climbing, Football